<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software engineering experiencies related blog</title>
    <description>Enric Forn  Innovation and Architecture Product Manager</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 22:51:53 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 22:51:53 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.6</generator>

    
      <item>
        <title>The Culture Code - Book Review</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;culture-in-organizations-really-matters-with-the-aim-of-learning-more-about-the-traits-existing-in-the-cultures-of-high-performance-teams-i-read-the-book-the-culture-code-here-is-my-brief-summary-of-this-amazing-book&quot;&gt;Culture in organizations really matters. With the aim of learning more about the traits existing in the cultures of high performance teams, I read the book “The Culture Code”. Here is my brief summary of this amazing book.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When companies with teams developing software start using new stacks and tools, it often implies working in a different way and therefore people needing to change
their behavior. This is the reason why I started reading this book, I wanted to find out the role of culture in these kinds of contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is basically into 5 parts: It starts with an impactful introduction, followed by the description of each of the key factors of successful cultures, and it ends with some  additional resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction-when-two-plus-two-equals-ten&quot;&gt;Introduction: When two plus two equals ten&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short but powerful, the introduction completely captured my attention with the example of an experiment involving the building of spaghetti towers (the winner is the one who builds the tallest tower with spaghettis). There are two teams: one of proficient high
school students and the other one of kindergarten students. To find out who wins, you will need to read the book! I will only detail the main characteristics of each team:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High School team
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Well-organized&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Procedural process&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Slow flow&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kindergarden team
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fail fast&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Direct communication&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Constant Experimentation&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;key-factors-for-successful-cultures&quot;&gt;Key Factors For Successful Cultures&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1st-key-factor-build-safety&quot;&gt;1st Key Factor: Build Safety&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building safety is key to ensure a good culture in your organization. The book details how some teams value this factor and how leaders or the team itself work to nurture safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can take many actions to build safety in your organization by using some of the examples described in this section. For instance, using belonging cues, like having coffee every morning with all your team members. It is really interesting how these little actions can contribute to create a feeling of safety. I recommend to you to try it out, as well as some of the other actions listed in the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2nd-key-factor-share-vulnerabilities&quot;&gt;2nd Key Factor: Share Vulnerabilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second key factor is sharing vulnerabilities. Once people feel safe in your organization, the second step is to invite people to honestly share their work challenges and concerns. This information must flow bidirectionally in the organization hierarchy, from the top down and from the bottom up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing the problems of your organization, is the first step towards solving them and becoming more efficient and effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From top down, it is important to clearly communicate any problems that have been identified in order for people to work on solving them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managers and leaders should allow for opportunities for everyone to safely share weaknesses, mistakes, setbacks,… In these spaces when vulnerability is detected, positive feedback needs to be provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colleagues from any organization must feel safe in order for them to be willing to share their difficulties and problems. If they do not feel like they are in a safe environment, they maight be afraid to share their vulnerabilities. They may not think that this information will be used to improve the system, but instead be used against them. In this instance, vulnerability will not be shared but hidden, which does not promote a positive culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting point in this section identifies people with specific skills (super -cooperators) like humility. Allow cooperation between people and teams, allow to share vulnerability, identify and solve problems faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section of the book also enumerates and describres some actions you can take to facilitate sharing vulnerabilities amongst with your teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3rd-key-factor-establish-purpose&quot;&gt;3rd Key Factor: Establish Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This third factor is less surprising than the other ones, but not less important. It is also really important to measure what really matters in order to evaluate if your organization is working in alignment with its purpose. One thing you could do to establish purpose is using catchphrases, such as “Work hard, be nice” (KIPP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This part of the book distinguishes two types of teams according to how you want to lead, for proficiency or for creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proficiency teams excel in specific and well-known tasks. So book details actions to focus this team  in this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creative teams perform at their best when they have autonomy to try new ideas, are trusted to fail fast and feedback is provided. Actions to focus this kind of team differs from a team focused on proficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this chapter, you find actions to establish purpose for each kind of team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;epilogue-acknowledgments-and-notes&quot;&gt;Epilogue, Acknowledgments and Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the book, the author explains his journey and gives thanks to many people who helped his project succeed. 
You will also find a lot of useful information and references that the author used to write the book, which you can use to go deeper if you are interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusions&quot;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion this book can help you understand how culture works inside an organization, and the benefits of cultivating a healthy culture within your organization. Each concept described above references real live examples from organizations; such as Navy Seals, Pixar, sports teams,… These examples clearly show the positive consequences of applying these actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have personally tried out some of these actions in my daily work. I have had surprising results, particularly with the actions to promote safety and sharing vulnerabilities amongst teams I have worked with. I fully recommend to you to apply some of these techniques at your daily workplace, as you will see positive changes in a short time. By adopting little changes you and your teams can achieve powerful results!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I completely agree with the ideas and actions explained in this book, you can figure out how to create a healthy culture in your organization that allows high performance team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that if you think to start some of these actions, you should take care of consistency between these three pilars: safety, share vulnerability and purpose. If your organization achieve it, then values and behaviours will also be aligned, and therefore a healhty culture, which will allow the creation of high-performance teams and better results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend you to buy and read this book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;float:middle;width:120px;height:240px&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://rcm-eu.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;amp;t=10dc87-21&amp;amp;m=amazon&amp;amp;o=30&amp;amp;p=8&amp;amp;l=as1&amp;amp;IS1=1&amp;amp;asins=1847941265&amp;amp;linkId=f5907f6da8339ed9a5f6014336ded424&amp;amp;bc1=FFFFFF&amp;amp;lt1=_top&amp;amp;fc1=333333&amp;amp;lc1=0066C0&amp;amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;amp;f=ifr&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading. I highly appreciate your feedback, so please contact me if you want to discuss about the book or this post.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/leadership/2020/01/14/the-culture-code-book-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/leadership/2020/01/14/the-culture-code-book-review/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Lessons learned from devops journey</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;in-this-post-you-will-find-five-points-considered-core-to-successfully-adopt-devops-i-should-recommend-you-to-follow-these-5-core-points-if-you-want-to-move-an-organization-towards-a-devops-transformation&quot;&gt;In this post you will find five points considered core to successfully adopt DevOps. I should recommend you to follow these 5 core points if you want to move an organization towards a DevOps transformation.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past ten years I’ve been guided on my DevOps journey by the aim to improve development cycle of the products I’ve been working on, and the desire of continuous learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DevOps technics and patterns are widely explained in many posts, books and podcasts. In this post I share five most important lessons learned in my DevOps journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-measure-your-development-process&quot;&gt;1. Measure your development process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eficiency and removing waste are two main objective key results that you should pursue in your DevOps journey. If you want to improve your software delivery performance, it’s important to drive your actions based on emphirical information. You should be able to measure the following metrics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- Lead time for changes&lt;/strong&gt;: many companies are efficient on using their resources, but their pace is too low. This indicator gives you information on how fast you can bring new business requirements to production environment, and can help you to balance resource usage and flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- Deployment frequency&lt;/strong&gt;: this indicator it’s highly correlater with batch sizes of your projects. As soon as you reduce batch sizing, it’s less complex deploy applications in production environment, and therefore, you will be able to deploy more frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- Mean time to restore service&lt;/strong&gt;: this measure captures the average time needed to recover your service from an incident like unplanned outage. This  time includes not only the time spent until you recover customer’s service, but also time spent to figure out the root cause and fix it in the production environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By collecting all this information from these indicators you are assessing which is your starting point. At this time, you can address objective conversations based on these data, and allows you to create the first backlog to improve your system. While monitoring these indicators, you will be able to check if your system is improved or not, in each changes delivered to your applications, tools or processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-show-business-value-to-managers&quot;&gt;2. Show business value to managers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless the size of the organization, you’ll need investment to improve your toolchain, refactor applications, update processes or teach your employees. It’s really important to map your efforts to monetization, in terms of improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By improving key performance indicators listed in point 1, first beneficiary is business in terms of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you improve your lead time, business will be able to deliver products to customers more quickly, and so your company will obtain profit with these products faster too.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By improving your frequency in deployment, this means your business will be able to deliver more frequently value to customers. Thus these customers will get more new features more frequently too.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you improve your mean time to recover service, you can traduce it to better service given to customers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-focus-on-a-learning-culture-in-your-organization&quot;&gt;3. Focus on a Learning culture in your organization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work on culture’s organization is one of the most difficult challenges to be addressed. DevOps is an enabler that allows your company to walk to a learning and innovation culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DevOps technics and practices are focused on improve speed, availability and cost reduction, and it’s necessary that everyone should be able to learn new approaches on how apply new technics, and experiment in their daily work. Create an innovation mindset, move people to continuously learn and be more open to change. When people embrace creativity, they are able to deliver smarter solutions for your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, when I work on improve a culture’s organization, I focus the efforts on try to figure out which kind of context allows the creation of high-performance teams, and I found these three points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build a safety environment&lt;/strong&gt; where everyone is comfortable to work together. All members in your team has skills to succeed delivering the product. One of the most difficult task create de context to motivate them. Use belonging cues every day (morning coffee) or weekly (breakfast on friday)  to include people in the team. The most awful part is when a person do not want to stay in a team working on a product, but they don’t want to leave, you must pick up trash and remove bad apples, and it’s not an easy task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share vulnerability&lt;/strong&gt; by creating spaces where you can talk on what you’ve done, and also discuss which actions the team want to take, in order to improve or change. Take out people from their confort zone at first is awkward, but has positive results. You can organize retrospective with teams, after the delivery of a feature in your product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Establish purpose&lt;/strong&gt; which guide outputs aligned to outcomes defined by business, through your products. This strategy enables alignment in the entire organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-achieve-big-through-small&quot;&gt;4. Achieve big through small&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very difficult to transform an organitzation in a short term. People need to learn step by step how to use new techniques and tools, and change their behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Innovation Curve of Rogers classify adopters and innovators into various categories, based on the idea that some people are more open to adapt to changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/lessons-learned-devops/rogers-innovation-curve.png&quot; alt=&quot;Rogers adoption/innovation &quot; title=&quot;Rogers adoption/innovation curve&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Innovation teams probably are the ones who are leading the DevOps transformation in your organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should propose you to identify the early adopters teams in your organization to start your DevOps transformation. Check your model with early adopters teams and refine it.  Collect KPIs before and after the adoption, and then extract metrics from your measurements. You should visualize the improvements as the teams are more comfortable and more productive while using devops toolchain. Overcommunicate all these results to the entire organization, and then expand that devops model step by step throughout your company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-your-devops-journey-never-ends&quot;&gt;5. Your DevOps journey never ends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, once you’ve started your DevOps journey it will never ends. Capabilities, processes and behaviours of teams, will probably change, and you technics, practices and platforms must also change. Observer your toolchain system and improve it. Keep your eye on these situations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New languages used by development team which are not supported by your pipeline.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New kinds of infrastructure where you want to deploy artifacts that you doesn’t support either.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The level of delegation you give to team for being more autonomous on doing some tasks (customize builds, quality parameter configuration, integration between requirements and development tools, …)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Figure out where pain point are in your SDLC. Deal with received feedback carefully.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stay tuned on what’s going on the community: many people innovate an try new tools and techniques. You can watch webinars and read many interesting books explaining deeply these techniques and succeeded use cases. Each organization adopt DevOps model through their own way, there’s no a road to follow. I should recommend to read these interesting books:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Gene Kim, Patrick Debois, John Willis, Jez Humble, John Allspaw: &lt;strong&gt;The DevOps Handbook&lt;/strong&gt;: How to Create World-Class Agility, Reliability, and Security in Technology Organizations Paperback – 2016&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Nicole Forsgren, Jez Humble, Gene Kim: &lt;strong&gt;Accelerate&lt;/strong&gt;: The Science of Lean Software and DevOps: Building and Scaling High Performing Technology Organizations Paperback – March , 2018&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Daniel Coyle: &lt;strong&gt;The Culture Code&lt;/strong&gt;: The Secrets of Highly Successful Groups - 2018&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Jez Humble, Joanne Molesky, Barry O’Reilly. &lt;strong&gt;Lean Enterprise&lt;/strong&gt;: How High Performance Organizations Innovate at Scale Hardcover – 2015&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope this post helps in your devops journey. Don’t hesitate contacting me for feedback or further information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/devops/2019/08/09/five-lessons-learned-from-devops-journey/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/devops/2019/08/09/five-lessons-learned-from-devops-journey/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intro DevOps</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Really excited for take part of this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/IGD-Tech-Drinks/events/255421279/&quot;&gt;meet up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so happy for having the chance of talking about DevOps, it seems many people is interested on this movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can take a look at this support &lt;a href=&quot;https://slides.com/enricforn/what-is-devops&quot;&gt;Intro DevOPs&lt;/a&gt; I used to guide my speech.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/devops/2018/10/24/intro-devops/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/devops/2018/10/24/intro-devops/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to measure a Team performance</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;briefly-description-of-which-metrics-you-should-choose-to-measure-how-fast-can-your-development-team-deliver-software-and-what-quality-does-that-deliverable&quot;&gt;Briefly description of which metrics you should choose to measure how fast can your development team deliver software, and what quality does that deliverable&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here follows  key metrics to measure your team performance to delivery valued features of a product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deployment frequency&lt;/strong&gt;: how often you deploy code to production environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lead time for changes&lt;/strong&gt;: how long does it take to go from code commit to code successfully running in production&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mean time to recover&lt;/strong&gt;: average time need to recover your service from an incident like unplanned outage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change failure rate&lt;/strong&gt;: what percentage of changes results either in degraded service or subsequently requires remediation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get this metrics by using tools to orchestrate your SDLC in a DevOps pipeline. Using tools such git as a SCM, CI/CD tool like Jenkins, monitoring your system with New Relic and tracing your developments in Jira.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft solution should be based in Visual Studio Team Services, which offers you a fully integrated ecosystem to implement your pipeline, and Azure to deploy and monitor your system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following metric is also really interested, but is focused on the performance of individuals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Morale&lt;/strong&gt;: is the enthusiasm and persistence with which a member of a team engages in the prescribed activities of that group’ (Manning, 1991)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/process/2018/10/19/how-to-measure-a-team-performance/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/process/2018/10/19/how-to-measure-a-team-performance/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Windows Server 2016 - install telnet from command-line</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-easiest-and-fastest-way-to-install-telnet-to-a-windows-server-2016-from-command-line&quot;&gt;The easiest and fastest way to install telnet to a Windows Server 2016 from command-line&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When trying to solve some kind of conectivity problem, I often use telnet. By default, windows machine do not preinstall telnet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;C:\&amp;gt;telnet google.com 80
'telnet' is not recognized as an internal or external command, operable program or batch file.
C:\&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can easily install telnet from command-line with this short command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From standard command prompt command-line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;dism /online /Enable-Feature /FeatureName:TelnetClient
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From powershell console:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Install-WindowsFeature -name Telnet-Client
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/windows/2017/07/05/windows-server-2016-install-telnet-from-command-line/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/windows/2017/07/05/windows-server-2016-install-telnet-from-command-line/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TFS 2017 Package Management Feature for npm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post I’ll explain briefly how to work with Visual Studio Package Management for npm. I suppose you are familiar with Visual Studio Team Services, NuGet (.NET libraries) and npm (javascript libraries).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you code your applications, you probably want to share libraries with other teams, in order to reuse code. Also you should supervise dependencies used by your applications, and you can reduce dependencies between them or avoid multiples packages doing the same action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve the first problem, you need to encapsule your code and then you can share that capsule. To solve de second problem, you need under control which dependencies can install the applications&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are using Visual Studio Team Services you can use (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/docs/package/overview&quot;&gt;Package Management feature&lt;/a&gt;) feature to store your packages. It supports two kinds of packages: npm and NuGet. I hope Package Management will support docker images in earlier versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s go configuring a npm package repo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to Package management feature, and add a new feed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/package-management-1.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;New Feed Creation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feed creation allows you to configure some options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Name and Description for this repository.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read permissions to this repository: only team members, or all members in the collection.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contribute permissions: who can upload packages to this repository, team members or only project collection build service. This permission try to force the upload of packages from a build process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enabling check ‘Include packages from npmjs.org’,  uses npmjs.org as a secondary scoped registry. It’s interesting when you want to use private packages and public packages from npmjs.org.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have create your repository, you can connect to it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/package-management-2.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Feed Connection&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can choose whether the access is through NuGet or npm. In this example we choose npm:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open a command-line.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install the auth helper by running this command: ‘npm install -g vsts-npm-auth –registry https://registry.npmjs.com’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Add your registry manually to your project by creating and .npmrc file at the root project, and adding the following configuration:
          registry=https://enformat.pkgs.visualstudio.com/_packaging/npm-packages/npm/registry
          always-auth=true
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/package-management-3.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;File creation with powershell&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Note that you can configure the access to this repository to download only release packages, prerelease or both, by adding a parameter:
          registry=https://enformat.pkgs.visualstudio.com/_packaging/npm-packages@Release/npm/registry
          registry=https://enformat.pkgs.visualstudio.com/_packaging/npm-packages@Prerelease/npm/registry&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Store credentials to home folder, by running the following command: ‘vsts-npm-auth -config .npmrc’. By running this command, the app asks for the credentials to store in the .npmrc file on your profile folder. In this example, I’m using Windows 10, and file was created to C:\Users\enric.npmrc.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/package-management-4.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Creating credentials to user profile folder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s highly recommended to create two files:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One at the root project that contains the configuration for the whole team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Another one to your home profile folder containing the your credentials in a secure mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we’ve configured our package with the url and the credentials to access to the feed, we’re ready to publish that package. This action is as easy typing command npm publish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/package-management-5.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Publish npm package&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now your package is ready for being installed to any application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/package-management-6.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Web access view from a published npm package&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy sharing code from your feeds with your colleagues!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tfs/alm/npm/2017/01/31/TFS-2017-Package-Management/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tfs/alm/npm/2017/01/31/TFS-2017-Package-Management/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Install AWSCli on windows</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;this-post-describe-how-to-install-awscli-on-windows-and-how-to-solve-encountered-issues&quot;&gt;This post describe how to install AWSCli on windows, and how to solve encountered issues&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services is a great cloud environment. Personnally I’m using its S3 service (&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/Welcome.html&quot;&gt;Simple Storage Service&lt;/a&gt;) to backup all my information. It’s really cheap and easy to access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/es/cli/&quot;&gt;AWSCli&lt;/a&gt; to interact with amazon web services. Most of actions you can do with their web console, can also be run from awscli.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just downloaded the application and installed it. Apparently is very easy, the install application is an easy wizard. After that, I opened a powershell console and configure a default credentials to access to my AWS account:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open powershell console (powershell.exe).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run command ‘aws configure’. This command ask you credentials to access to AWS:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Access Key Id: This key&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Secret Access Key: Key showed only when you create the user.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Default Region: in my case eu-west-1&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Default output format: I chose json&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems everything works fine, but when I ran the next command (aws s3 cp s://mybucket D:\data\mybucket.) the following error appears:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C:\Program Files\Amazon\AWSCLI.\dateutil\parser.py:336: UnicodeWarning: Unicode  equal comparison failed to convert both arguments to Unicode - interpreting them as being unequal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an error with python 2.7.9 version, which was solved in earlier versions of python. And this is the python version that awscli installs to run properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can run command ‘aws –version’ to know which version of python is using your installed awscli:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS C:\Users\enric&amp;gt; aws –version
aws-cli/1.11.38 Python/2.7.9 Windows/10 botocore/1.5.1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to solve this issue, I started to find a solution in google. And I found an opened issue in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/aws/aws-cli/issues/424&quot;&gt;github awscli&lt;/a&gt;. I hope AWS guys will solve it in the next version :). There I found the workaround to solve this issue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uninstall AWSCli from my machine.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install the latest version of python.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Install awscli from python 3 installer: open a powershell console. Run commmand ‘pip install awscli’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the awscli installed on my machine, is using a newer version of python and works fine:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS C:\Users\enric&amp;gt; aws –version
aws-cli/1.11.38 Python/3.6.0 Windows/10 botocore/1.5.1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you encounter the same issue, hope this helps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/aws/2017/01/18/Install-AWSCli-On-Windows/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/aws/2017/01/18/Install-AWSCli-On-Windows/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Configure on premise build server to Visual Studio Team Services</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;describing-on-how-to-connect-your-build-server-to-a-team-project-on-visual-studio-team-services&quot;&gt;Describing on how to connect your Build server to a team project on Visual Studio Team Services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post I suppose you are familiar to Visual Studio Team Services (from now VSTS). I’m gonna explain briefly how you can configure your own build server hosted on premise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build service is the feature from Visual Studio Team Services to automate your build process. Build service allows you to build your code, and run several tasks to assure your code quality. After this process you can create a release definition and deploy it to your environments. You can use a hosted build controller to run a build process after you check-in to source control (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visualstudio.com/docs/tfvc/overview&quot;&gt;TFVC&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/docs/git/gitquickstart&quot;&gt;GIT&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can configure your project to build automatically by following this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/docs/build/get-started/dot-net&quot;&gt;guide&lt;/a&gt;. This example is based on a standard .NET for Windows application, but VSTS Build can support any language and platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, let’s suppose we want to run &lt;a href=&quot;https://winscp.net&quot;&gt;WinSCP&lt;/a&gt; from our build process, and we need FileZilla to be installed in the build server. First of all, we would review if WinSCP is installed on a hosted build controller in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://listofsoftwareontfshostedbuildserver.azurewebsites.net/&quot;&gt;list of software&lt;/a&gt;. WinSCP is not installed on hosted build servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we must use WinSCP during our release process, then we should to create our own build server, in order to set up with all software we need to run in our build process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we compare build process from TFS2013 and before, the concept is slightly different: Controller instances do not exists, you only define queues and agents. Your queue can be configured as hosted or not. This means that you are using hosted server builds, or you configure agents hosted on premise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Access your admin panel to download the agent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/download-agent.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Build Service Configuration&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your platform, download the appropriate agent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/download-agent-2.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Download agent depending on your platform&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless which agent you configure, you should create a specific user to run this service. This user needs powerful permissions to do many tasks on your environment, and you should secure it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Configure Build Agent in VSTS or TFS15&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are using VSTS or TFS15 then download standard image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before running the agent configuration, you need to create a personal access token to access for VSTS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/agent-config-2.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Creating a personal access token&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are using VSTS or TFS15 then download standard image and run ./config.cmd from command line to configure, its pretty easy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/agent-config-1.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Configuring build agent VSTS&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the image below, build agents are configured and running have a green flag. On the right side, you can see a list of builds that previously ran:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/agent-config-3.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Configured build agent VSTS&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Configure Build Agent in TFS2013&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your VSTS or TFS version is older then you should download the legacy version, and then the following step differs a little bit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all you should to keep in mind this point: you need to open TCP port 9191 in your firewall, in order to allow VSTS to connect to the service installed in you machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the port service is opened you can configure the agent by running ./configure.cmd from command line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/Configure-agent-powershell-command.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Configured build agent VSTS&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In windows environment, create agent as service, allows you to manage service from server without access to VSTS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/Agent-created-as-a-service.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;VSTS Build Agent configured as service&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/visual%20studio/builds/2016/11/02/Visual-Studio-Team-Services-Build-Service-On-Premise/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/visual%20studio/builds/2016/11/02/Visual-Studio-Team-Services-Build-Service-On-Premise/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Connect to TFS2013 or  Visual Studio Online and access to WorkItemStore</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-connect-to-tfs-or-visual-studio-online-through-api-and-get-workitemstore-service-brief-description-of-encountered-issues-and-how-to-solve-them&quot;&gt;How to connect to TFS or Visual Studio online through API and get WorkItemStore service. Brief description of encountered issues and how to solve them.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I detail how you can access to Team Foundation Server 2013 (on premise) through its API. Once we can connect to the server, we will get an instance of a TFS service, in this example we will access to WorkItemStore, and we’ll get a list of all existing user stories in a team project. I suppouse you are familiar to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visualstudio.com/en-us/products/tfs-overview-vs.aspx&quot;&gt;TFS&lt;/a&gt;, and you are used to work with &lt;a href=&quot;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/hh409275.aspx&quot;&gt;WorkItems&lt;/a&gt;) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/bb130306.c#&quot;&gt;WIQL&lt;/a&gt;.
Ok, let’s start with a sample c# console application called TFSUserStoriesConsole. Open your Visual Studio and create a new Visual C# Console Application (File -&amp;gt; New -&amp;gt; Project -&amp;gt; Visual C#). Then we create a class which manage connection to TFS, and get the instance of WorkItemStore object. WorkItemStore let you to get workitems from TFS. Let me show you a piece of code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;     teamProjectCollection = new TfsTeamProjectCollection(tfsUri, myCredentials);

     teamProjectCollection.EnsureAuthenticated();

     workItemStore = teamProjectCollection.GetService&amp;lt;WorkItemStore&amp;gt;();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We connect to TFS, ensure we are connected to it, and finally we get the instance of WorkItemStore. It’s strange because workItemStore equals null and I don’t get more information about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I’ve found to get more information about this null, is create a new instance of WorkItemStore:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;     WorkItemStore workItemStore = new WorkItemStore(teamProjectCollection);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case seems that I missed some assemblies to reference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Type: System.IO.FileNotFoundException
Message: Could not load file or assembly ‘Microsoft.TeamFoundation.WorkItemTracking.Proxy, Version=14.0.0.0, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=b03f5f7f11d50a3a’ or one of its dependencies. The system cannot find the file specified.
Source: Microsoft.TeamFoundation.WorkItemTracking.Client
StackTrace:    at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.WorkItemTracking.Client.WorkItemStore.InitializeInternal()
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.WorkItemTracking.Client.WorkItemStore.Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Client.ITfsTeamProjectCollectionObject.Initialize(TfsTeamProjectCollection teamProjectCollection)
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Client.TfsTeamProjectCollection.InitializeTeamFoundationObject(String fullName, Object instance)
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Client.TfsConnection.CreateServiceInstance(Assembly assembly, String fullName)
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Client.TfsConnection.GetServiceInstance(Type serviceType, Object serviceInstance)
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Client.TfsTeamProjectCollection.GetServiceInstance(Type serviceType, Object serviceInstance)
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Client.TfsConnection.GetService(Type serviceType)
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Client.TfsConnection.GetService&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;T&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, much easier getting a stacktrace to solve the problem. I added that reference, but I get another error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Message: Error HRESULT E_FAIL has been returned from a call to a COM component.
Source: Microsoft.TeamFoundation.WorkItemTracking.Client.DataStoreLoader
StackTrace:    at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.WorkItemTracking.Client.DataStore.DataStoreNative.UpdateMetadata(IntPtr handle, Object rowset, String dbstamp, UInt32&amp;amp; changes)
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.WorkItemTracking.Client.DataStore.Datastore.UpdateMetadata(Object rowset, String dbstamp)
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.WorkItemTracking.Client.WorkItemStore.EndBackendCall(BackendCallData data)
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.WorkItemTracking.Client.WorkItemStore.RefreshCacheInternal(BackendCallData&amp;amp; data)
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.WorkItemTracking.Client.WorkItemStore.InitializeInternal()
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.WorkItemTracking.Client.WorkItemStore.Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Client.ITfsTeamProjectCollectionObject.Initialize(TfsTeamProjectCollection teamProjectCollection)
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Client.TfsTeamProjectCollection.InitializeTeamFoundationObject(String fullName, Object instance)
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Client.TfsConnection.CreateServiceInstance(Assembly assembly, String fullName)
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Client.TfsConnection.GetServiceInstance(Type serviceType, Object serviceInstance)
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Client.TfsTeamProjectCollection.GetServiceInstance(Type serviceType, Object serviceInstance)
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Client.TfsConnection.GetService(Type serviceType)
   at Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Client.TfsConnection.GetService&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;T&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case I monitor the process with &lt;a href=&quot;https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/sysinternals/bb896645&quot;&gt;FileMon&lt;/a&gt; and the process ends with an access denied to folder   C:\ProgramData\Microsoft Team Foundation\4.0\Cache&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I gave write permissions to C:\ProgramData\Microsoft Team Foundation\4.0\Cache the application runs properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find this errors when you install it to a server which is not TFS data tier and without Visual Studio installed either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sample code can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/enricforn/sampleapplications/tree/master/csharp/TFSUserStoriesConsole&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope it helps and you save time to solve this problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tfs/visual%20studio/2015/02/23/access-workItemstore-tfs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tfs/visual%20studio/2015/02/23/access-workItemstore-tfs/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi all. Welcome to personal blog of Enric Forn. I will write in english, but also in catalan or spanish language. I will post about software engineering, software automation and distributed teams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/general/2015/02/21/welcome/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/general/2015/02/21/welcome/</guid>
      </item>
    

    
      
        
          <item>
            <title></title>
            <description>&lt;!----------------------------------------------------------------
     _ _           _ _          
  __| | |__  _   _| | |         Ascii arts included in this page:
 / _` | '_ \| | | | | |         - R2D2, provided by: https://www.chris.com/
| (_| | |_) | |_| | | |         - Texts, generated from: https://www.network-science.de/ascii/
 \__,_|_.__/ \__, |_|_|         https://github.com/dbtek/dbyll
-------------|___/------------------------------------------------&gt;

  &lt;style&gt;
    pre {
          background: none;
          border: none;
    }
  &lt;/style&gt;

  &lt;pre&gt;

                       444444444       000000000            444444444   
                      4::::::::4     00:::::::::00         4::::::::4  
                     4:::::::::4   00:::::::::::::00      4:::::::::4  
                    4::::44::::4  0:::::::000:::::::0    4::::44::::4  
                   4::::4 4::::4  0::::::0   0::::::0   4::::4 4::::4  
                  4::::4  4::::4  0:::::0     0:::::0  4::::4  4::::4  
                 4::::4   4::::4  0:::::0     0:::::0 4::::4   4::::4  
                4::::444444::::4440:::::0 000 0:::::04::::444444::::444
                4::::::::::::::::40:::::0 000 0:::::04::::::::::::::::4
                4444444444:::::4440:::::0     0:::::04444444444:::::444
                          4::::4  0:::::0     0:::::0          4::::4  
                          4::::4  0::::::0   0::::::0          4::::4  
                          4::::4  0:::::::000:::::::0          4::::4  
                        44::::::44 00:::::::::::::00         44::::::44
                        4::::::::4   00:::::::::00           4::::::::4
                        4444444444     000000000             4444444444

         ,-----.             _   _     _           _                 _     _               _   
       ,'_/_|_\_`.          | |_| |__ (_)___   ___| |__   ___  _   _| | __| |  _ __   ___ | |_ 
      /&lt;&lt;::8[O]::&gt;\         | __| '_ \| / __| / __| '_ \ / _ \| | | | |/ _` | | '_ \ / _ \| __|
     _|-----------|_        | |_| | | | \__ \ \__ \ | | | (_) | |_| | | (_| | | | | | (_) | |_ 
 :::|  | ====-=- |  |:::     \__|_| |_|_|___/ |___/_| |_|\___/ \__,_|_|\__,_| |_| |_|\___/ \__|
 :::|  | -=-==== |  |:::                                                                         
 :::\  | ::::|()||  /:::     _                                                          
 ::::| | ....|()|| |::::    | |__   __ _ _ __  _ __   ___ _ __       _____   _____ _ __ 
     | |_________| |        | '_ \ / _` | '_ \| '_ \ / _ \ '_ \     / _ \ \ / / _ \ '__|
     | |\_______/| |        | | | | (_| | |_) | |_) |  __/ | | |_  |  __/\ V /  __/ |   
    /   \ /   \ /   \       |_| |_|\__,_| .__/| .__/ \___|_| |_( )  \___| \_/ \___|_|   
    `---' `---' `---'                   |_|   |_|              |/                       


    &lt;/pre&gt;</description>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/404.html</link>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
        
      
    
      
        
          <item>
            <title>About</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Love mountain-biking and montaineering. Learning how to improve software development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <link>http://localhost:4000/about.html</link>
          </item>
        
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>